<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog Posts on Jose Ibarra</title>
    <link>//www.icepicky.com/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog Posts on Jose Ibarra</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 25 Oct 2018 19:24:25 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="//www.icepicky.com/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Yearly Theme 2022</title>
      <link>//www.icepicky.com/blog/yearly-theme-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jan 2022 09:10:05 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//www.icepicky.com/blog/yearly-theme-2022/</guid>
      <description>I was introduced to themes from this video.
After reflecting on my theme from last year and how I&amp;rsquo;m feeling now, I realize that I mostly want to continue what I established last year. I want to build on the foundation that I lay and expand it to areas that I feel like I&amp;rsquo;m missing.
I&amp;rsquo;ve decided my theme for 2022 is the year of foundation. I want to establish the foundation for who I am for the next few years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reflecting on 2021: Year of Quality</title>
      <link>//www.icepicky.com/blog/reflecting-on-2021-year-of-quality/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Jan 2022 09:09:24 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//www.icepicky.com/blog/reflecting-on-2021-year-of-quality/</guid>
      <description>My life at the start of 2021 2021 started as one of the most stressful periods of times for me as an adult. I typically keep my work life and personal life separated well but work stresses from the end of 2020 and beginning of 2021 affected my mood and seeped into my personal life. I was the lead for a project that was estimated to take 3 months and we needed to deliver in 2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review: The Last of Us Part Two</title>
      <link>//www.icepicky.com/blog/the-last-of-us-part-two/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Mar 2021 10:07:32 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//www.icepicky.com/blog/the-last-of-us-part-two/</guid>
      <description>Warning: There will be major spoilers in this review, particularly about the beginning and end of the game.
I received The Last of Us Part 2 has a birthday present. I subsequently binge played the game in under 2 weeks, savoring every bit of it. The story of the game is very strong and it has good gameplay (mixed with some bad) to entertain in between the engrossing story bits.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Improving My Communication</title>
      <link>//www.icepicky.com/blog/improving-my-communication/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 May 2020 07:37:14 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//www.icepicky.com/blog/improving-my-communication/</guid>
      <description>Recently, I&amp;rsquo;ve been reading a lot to supplement my career development. I&amp;rsquo;ve slowly come to the realization that the greatest thing I can do to further my career is by improving my communication:
 My thoughts will be more clear and concise. This will help build my arguments and improve my persuasive capabilities. Discussions outside of engineering will be a lot easier. I&amp;rsquo;ll be able to relay my ideas to non-engineers a lot better.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tier Lists</title>
      <link>//www.icepicky.com/blog/tier-lists/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Dec 2018 19:35:03 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//www.icepicky.com/blog/tier-lists/</guid>
      <description>While at General Motors, I had a lot of opinionated discussions with friends. These conversations varied in topic and some of them involved ranking things in categories. After many of these discussions, I decided to create lists to rank the categories we discussed to compare with others. Unfortunately, I was the only one to create large and comrehensive tier lists.
This is a compilation of the tier lists I&amp;rsquo;ve created.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creep Review</title>
      <link>//www.icepicky.com/blog/creep-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Oct 2018 19:28:23 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//www.icepicky.com/blog/creep-review/</guid>
      <description>The Creep movie series is a frightening exploration of a realistic situation with a mentally unstable person.
The realism of these movies is part of the reason they&amp;rsquo;re so scary. Instead of improbable situations or supernatural occurrences, everything is pretty much grounded in reality. The antagonist has mental health issues that drive him to be a serial killer and stalker. He acts just normal enough that you can believe his friendliness but he&amp;rsquo;s just weird enough to leave you unsettled.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This is my first post</title>
      <link>//www.icepicky.com/blog/test/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Feb 2018 16:04:28 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//www.icepicky.com/blog/test/</guid>
      <description>Nothing much to see here</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>