<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Jose Ibarra</title>
    <link>http://www.icepicky.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Jose Ibarra</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 Apr 2018 14:58:26 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://www.icepicky.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Resume</title>
      <link>http://www.icepicky.com/resume/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Apr 2018 14:58:26 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.icepicky.com/resume/</guid>
      <description>Qualifications  7 years of Java experience; 3 years of Javascript experience; 2 years of C++ experience 1.5 years of data visualization research experience Developed a mainframe and Java application to manage part logistics, orders, and inventory for General Motors Developed mobile applications for Sandia National Labs Developed smaller applications in free time and hackathons, including augmented reality resource finder app, calendar and vehicle scheduling app, and autonomous vehicle scheduling app.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This is my first post</title>
      <link>http://www.icepicky.com/posts/test/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Feb 2018 16:04:28 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.icepicky.com/posts/test/</guid>
      <description>Nothing much to see here</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Legato - Autonomous Vehicle Manager</title>
      <link>http://www.icepicky.com/projects/legato/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Nov 2016 13:18:54 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.icepicky.com/projects/legato/</guid>
      <description>This application was created for the 2016 General Motors National Hackathon Championships. It integrates the user&amp;rsquo;s life with autonomous vehicle services.
The application utilizes calendars provided by the user to schedule events for your autonomous car to use. The application can automatically suggest events by querying the OnStar API for things like oil levels. Calendar events and destinations display on the Android app so the user is aware of their car&amp;rsquo;s location.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Travalet - OnStar Integrated Car Scheduler</title>
      <link>http://www.icepicky.com/projects/travalet/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Sep 2016 13:47:38 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.icepicky.com/projects/travalet/</guid>
      <description>This application was created for the 2016 General Motors Arizona Hackathon. It integrates the user&amp;rsquo;s email events with existing OnStar services.
The applciation utilizes Google&amp;rsquo;s Gmail API to find events in the future and automatically schedule oil changes, tire pressure stops and gas station stops. The application utilized different stop and end times for events, such as waking up the user, starting the car and the car leaving for the final destination.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>INSPIR3.com - Development &amp; Design</title>
      <link>http://www.icepicky.com/projects/inspir3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Aug 2016 13:47:27 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.icepicky.com/projects/inspir3/</guid>
      <description>This website was created for INSPIR3 - Mental Wellness Center in the summer of 2016. The website is a basic static website that describes the vision and goals of INSPIR3 and promotes their capital campaign.
The website utilizes the Foundation framework from ZURB for the design of the website. Node.js is the HTTP server for the website and the blogging platform used for the website. The HTTP server utilized Express.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Surname Search - Surname Population Density &amp; Income Distribution</title>
      <link>http://www.icepicky.com/projects/surname-search/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Apr 2014 13:47:54 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.icepicky.com/projects/surname-search/</guid>
      <description>This application was developed for my undergraduate honors thesis and was accepted and published at EuroVA 2014. The work was supported partially from an award from U.S. Department of Homeland Security’s VACCINE Center and a grant from the Engineering and Physical Sciences Research Council UK EPSRC. It received surname input from the user and output a population density map and income distribution for that surname.
The application combined Java web services and MySQL on the backend and HTML, Javascript, d3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Linked Animal-Human Health Visual Analytics (LAHVA) Expansion</title>
      <link>http://www.icepicky.com/projects/lahva/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2013 13:48:06 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.icepicky.com/projects/lahva/</guid>
      <description>This application was developed for the Spring 2013 Fulton Undergraduate Research Initiative (FURI). The application allowed users to load a health and weather data set to display graphically on a map. The map displayed the counties for a country and changed the color of a county based on the number of health incidents. The user could change the the health condition (such as gastrointestinal problems) or the weather condition (such as temperature).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>